原创翻译  双语字幕
《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
我的家人是来自一个叫纳尔托尔的星球
My family is from a planet called Naltor.
我们种族的一些女性可以梦见未来
Some of our women can dream the future.
翻译     DustD  洗七里  DerbyNinja
要是我们能让人类也有超能力呢
What if we could make people super?
你想告诉我你成功做到了这个
Are you telling me that you've achieved this?
如果艾丽克斯的记忆没有被抹去
If Alex's mind isn't wiped, there is a 100% certainty
翻译     阿p  左左  C·A
哈雷百分之百会发现你的秘密身份
that Haley will discover your secret identity.
校对     肉松  饿得慌
准备好了吗
Ready?
时间轴    想念Gallifrey的Wholock  三水
后期     你是不是饿得慌
总监     你是不是饿得慌
非常好
再来一次
快点  快点
调高
-哥们  你看到了吗  -是啊  那猫真蠢
- Dude, did you see that? - Yeah, that cat's so dumb.
不是  是药片  它们在发光
No, the pills. They're glowing.
杰瑞  你能安静点吗  我明天有化学测试
Jerry. Can you please keep it down? I have a chem test tomorrow.
杰瑞  伙计  我以为你所谓的上门服务
Jerry, bro. I thought the point of your mobile door-to-door service
是你为我送货上门呢
was that you came to my door?
给你  包你嗨的药片
Here you go. Guaranteed happiness in pill form,
美国品质保障
just like America promised.
-谢谢  -这些看起来  挺欢乐的
- Thank you. - These look... Fun.
杰瑞  为什么斯宾塞变成打了激素的海格
Jerry, why does Spencer look like Hagrid on steroids?
不知道  但我们或许该...
No idea, but we should, um,
赶紧离开这里  快走
get the hell out of here. Go!
攻击卡
Attack card.
-休想  -不
- No. - No!
-这已经是第五次了  -这意味着我赢了
- That's the fifth time. - That means I win.
我不理解这个游戏
I don't understand this game.
这些不是猫  也不会爆炸
These are not kittens, nor do they explode.
我很喜欢你们这种活动
Well, I love that you guys do this.
游戏之夜是我们家里的重要活动
Game night was a staple in my family.
你在哪里长大的  尼娅
Where did you grow up, Nia?
北边一个叫帕瑟斯的小镇
A small town up north called Parthas.
那不是爱尔兰语里的"天堂"吗  标准很高哦
Doesn't that mean "Paradise" In Irish? It's a pretty high bar.
何止是天堂
Paradise is an understatement.
那个小镇不仅美丽
The town's not just beautiful,
而且人类和外星人一起和谐生活
but aliens and humans have lived together
有数十年之久
in harmony for decades.
我这周末正好要回去过丰收节
I'm actually going back this weekend for Harvest Fest.
-然后  -保龄球
- And... - The Bowl Game!
*丹弗斯姐妹  我们行*
* Danvers sisters Yes, we can *
*你要不行  丹弗斯行*
* If you can't do it Danvers can *
不行不行  你们俩不能又组队
No! No! You two cannot be on the same team again.
我同意  你们从小就有各种姐妹笑话和密语
I agree. Inside jokes, short-hand from Midvale.
这种优势不公平
This is an unfair advantage.
-所以呢  -没准我们也有不公平的优势
- So? - Hey, but, you know, maybe we have an unfair advantage, too.
你也许说得对  人类最伟大的发明是什么
You could be right. Greatest human invention?
-电灯  -印刷机
- The electric light. - Printing press.
-失败  -好了  该我们了
- Fail. - Okay. Our turn.
简单  我最爱的电影
Easy! My favorite movie?
《中央舞台》
Center Stage.
什么
Excuse me?
怎么了  你花了一夏天学里边的红鞋舞
What? You spent an entire summer learning the red shoe dance.
你撞坏了三盏台灯
You broke three lamps.
不是  好吧
No. Okay, um...
《终结者2》
Terminator 2? Duh.
不  那是你最爱的电影  开动脑筋  艾丽克斯
No, that's your favorite. Come on, Alex! Think!
我脑子一片空白
I'm totally blanking.
有工作  从不让人失望
Duty calls. Never fails.
至少哈雷不在
Well, at least Haley's out of town.
抱歉  各位
Sorry, guys.
不  没事的
Oh, no, it's gonna be okay.
没什么大事
There's nothing too end-of-the-worldly.
就只是纳欣诺大学有外星人打群架
It's just an alien brawl at NCU.
-再见  -好吧
- See ya. - Right. Okay.
感谢你的帮助
Thank you for your assistance,
超女  之后交给我们吧
Supergirl. We'll take it from here.
很高兴能帮上忙  艾丽克斯
Happy to help, Alex.
还有一件事  我衷心希望你
One more thing. I would really appreciate it
能称我为丹弗斯局长
if you would address me as Director Danvers.
当然  没问题  丹弗斯局长
Yes, of course, Director Danvers.
超 女
第四季 第十一集
你发现你手上拿了两个甜甜圈
You realize you have two donuts in your hands,
而且味道还不搭吗
and that those don't even go together?
-是吗  -是
- Do I? - Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
我或许是在借吃甜甜圈消愁
I may be eating my feelings.
是艾丽克斯
It's Alex.
我还以为在抹除记忆后就能相安无事
I thought we were good after the mind wipe,
但我错了
but I was wrong.
昨晚她跟我说话的方式
The way she spoke to me last night,
对超女
to Supergirl...
她相当冷漠
She was so cold.
她不知道你是超女
She doesn't know that you're Supergirl.
我知道  只是没意识到那有多伤人
I know. Just didn't realize how much it would hurt.
她竟然不知道我最喜欢的电影是《绿野仙踪》
I mean, not knowing that my favorite movie is The Wizard of Oz?
伊莉莎认为我会对
Eliza thought that I would relate
这种年轻小姑娘
to the adventures of a young girl
在遥远国度的迷失冒险产生共情
being lost in a faraway land.
那是我最喜欢的电影
It was... It was my favorite movie,
因为我来自不同的星球
because I was from a different planet.
但是艾丽克斯却不知道这一点
And now, Alex doesn't know that.
不再知道了
Not anymore.
是啊  这会让人很难过
Yeah. It's gotta be tough.
真抱歉  这对你来说一定很艰难
I'm sorry. That must be really hard for you.
如果抹除记忆有我们
What if the mind wipe has consequences
没预计到的副作用呢
that we didn't anticipate?
你不能这么想
You can't think that way.
没准现在最好的做法
Look, maybe the best course of action right now
就是让你自己投身于工作之中
is to throw yourself into your work
不再去想这些事情
and just take your mind off of it.
奥尔森先生  抱歉  不是时候吗
Mr. Olsen... I'm sorry. Is this a bad time?
没有没有  我正要  吃甜甜圈吗
No. No. I was, um... Donut?
我不吃糖  或是面团  或是早餐
I don't eat sugar. Or dough. Or breakfast.
你沾到了巧克力...
You've got chocolate on your...
糟糕
Oh. Oops.
最好去一下洗手间
Better use the ladies' room.
抱歉
Excuse me.
奥尔森先生  我想推一条报道  但是...
Mr. Olsen, I wanted to pitch you a story, but it's, um...
-请吧  -这事有些敏感
- Please. -It's kind of sensitive.
没事  不用担心
Yeah. No worries.
是关于L公司和卢瑟女士的
It's about L-Corp and Ms. Luthor.
我在会计部门的线人
My source in the accounting department
在他们的财报里找到了漏洞
found a glitch in their numbers,
发现了不少的"黑预算"
caught rumors of a "Black budget."
他认为那和基因测试有关
He thinks it has to do with genetic testing.
基因测试又不违法
Genetic testing isn't illegal.
如果不是见不得人  为什么要瞒报
If it wasn't shady, why would they keep it off the books?
那么  我能去追踪这笔钱吗
So, can I follow the money?
行  但要把结果先发给我
Yeah. But send me what you have first.
我想要确认一下
I wanna vet it.
我知道我向妈妈保证过这周末回家的
I know I promised Mom I'd be home this weekend.
我也想回去  但是...
I planned to, but--
梅芙  我哪有那么不负责任
Maeve, I'm not terminally irresponsible.
我的航班取消是因为所有航班都取消了
My flight was canceled because all of the flights were canceled.
我现在不能走  我有工作
Well, I can't leave now because I have a job.
好  我尽量
Okay, I'll try.
我也爱你  拜
I love you, too. Bye.
是我姐姐  关系虽好
Sister. We're close,
但有时真的要被逼疯了
but, um, she drives me crazy.
我可以理解
I can relate to that.
我每年丰收节都会参加
I've never missed Harvest Fest.
你今天可以请假  詹姆斯不会介意的
You should take the day off. James won't mind.
要开车很久  你也知道我...
It's a long drive and you know I...
总会莫名其妙睡着吗  我知道
Fall asleep at weird times? I know.
是啊
Yeah.
那我来开车
So, I'll drive.
什么  你要跟我一起去吗
What? You'd... You'd come with me?
当然  你老家不是有名的包容之都吗
Yeah. Your town's like an oasis of tolerance, right?
我可以跟詹姆斯说那里可以出篇报道
So, I'll just pitch a story idea about it to James.
卡拉  那就太好了
Kara, that would be amazing.
公路旅行第一条戒律
First commandment of road trips...
必须服从司机的音乐品位
Thou shalt defer to the driver's choice of music.
这些不是淤青  只是毒素
Those are not bruises, simply toxins.
被求真者拉到了皮肤表面
Pulled to the surface by the Truth Seeker.
别担心  很快就会消失
Not to worry, they'll vanish soon.
但愿如此
I hope so.
就是感觉不对劲
Something just doesn't feel right.
也许这个能让你好受些
Perhaps this will make you feel better.
我已经查清了我们昨晚抓到的种族身份
I've discovered the species we apprehended last night.
是人类吗
They're human?
不  不只是人类
No, not just human...
还是兄弟会成员
Frat boys.
你妈妈是什么时候从纳尔托尔过来的
So, when did your mom come from Naltor?
18岁的时候
When she was 18.
她逃离那颗星球的前一晚
The night before she fled her planet,
梦到了一座农舍
she had a dream about a farmhouse
在那里她会遇到真爱
where she would meet her true love.
她还看到了一组随机坐标
And she saw a bunch of random coordinates
她把坐标录入到了太空船中
that she plugged into her craft,
后来她降落在了地球上的帕瑟斯
and she landed on Earth in Parthas.
一个人类家庭收留了她  他们是农夫
A human family took her in, farmers.
她爱上了他们的儿子
And she fell in love with their son.
我父亲
My dad.
没错  我觉得那里就是我命中注定的故乡
Yeah. I can't imagine having grown up anywhere else.
因为你的父母来自两个不同的星球吗
Because you have parents from two different planets?
对  以及我是变性人
Yeah, but also because I'm trans.
我一直知道我是个女孩
I always knew that I was a girl.
我的父母特别好
My parents were amazing.
他们支持我追求自我
They affirmed my authentic self
也在儿时帮助我成功变性
and helped me transition young.
我在帕瑟斯一直能够坦然做自己
I've always been able to be open about who I was in Parthas.
虽然这并不容易
I'm not saying it was easy.
当时也确实有人不理解
There were definitely people who didn't understand.
但那座城的包容精神很强大
But the town's ethos of inclusion is strong.
如果我在其他地方长大
And I think if I grew up anywhere else,
一定会更加艰难
it would've been a lot tougher.
谢谢你跟我分享这些
Thank you for sharing that with me.
当然
Of course.
还有一件事  你见到我家人时
Just one other thing, when you meet my family,
请不要说起我的梦境能力
please don't mention the dreaming powers.
我还没有告诉他们
It's just that I haven't told them yet.
从小到大我跟我姐无话不谈
And I've never kept a secret from my sister.
我一直很有负担
It's been weighing on me.
我理解那种感觉
Yeah, I know that feeling.
我不会说的
I won't say a word.
谢谢
Thank you.
还好是我开车
Good thing I drove.
是啊
Yeah, good thing.
我们在你的身体内发现了
We found traces of an unknown drug
带有外星记号的未知毒素
with alien markers in your system.
是什么毒素  你从哪里拿到的
What is it and where did you get it?
阿司匹林  瓶装的
Aspirin. From a bottle.
这就是我们平时总吃的东西
Man, it's the same stuff we take all the freaking time.
-但这一次不一样  -怎么不一样
- This time, it was different. - Different how?
我只感觉到愤怒  不是令人愉悦的那种
All I felt was rage, and not the fun kind.
那种药片通常会让你变得很嗨
They usually just make you happy.
-应该是质量不好  -我们惹上麻烦了吗
- Bad batch, I guess. - Are we in trouble?
你有六项袭击罪名  确实很麻烦
I have you on six counts of assault. So, yeah.
但如果你们能说出毒贩的名字  可以谈谈
But if you give me the name of your dealer, maybe we can talk.
不如我把我律师的名字给你  缉毒警察
How about I give you the name of my lawyer, narc?
-你还好吗  -没事  不  我不好
- Are you okay? - Yeah... Uh, no.
里面这帮蠢货  连新生测试都过不了
No, those idiots in there, they can't pass freshman comp,
我却撬不开他们的嘴  为什么
and yet I couldn't crack them. Why?
我回答不了这个问题
I don't have that answer.
但我知道这些良民为什么会黑化
But I do know why our Jekylls became Hydes.
他们体内注射的物质
The substance they ingested was radicalized
用15到19赫兹的伽马射线辐射过
by 15-to-the-19th power hertz worth of gamma rays.
有人辐射了他们的派对毒品吗
Someone irradiated their party drug?
你们到底怎么了  小朋友们
What happened to you, little guys?
为什么这么生气呢
Why did you get so angry, huh?
原因并不重要
Doesn't matter why.
重要的是我们如何利用这个来赚钱
All that matters is how we capitalize on it.
快看  半小时一万六千的阅读量
Here, check this out! 16,000 views just in the last hour.
一万六千  怎么可能...
Sixteen thousand? Holy...
我们火了
We're famous.
不  我们发财了  快看评论
No. No, we're rich. Here, check out the comments.
"我也要他们吃的东西"  康涅狄格州的苏说
"I'll have what they're having." Sue in Connecticut.
"我的年终奖都要用来买这个"
"I'd pay my entire bonus for that."
可以啊  东城萨姆·R
Yeah, Sam R. In East City!
我们手上有货啊
We have the supply.
走啊  满足群众的需求去
Shoot, let's go, uh, meet our demand.
杰瑞  我们为什么要走
Jerry. Why are we going?
别激动  小宝贝
Just chill, Little Squeak.
等我们发财了  你会连大学都不想上了
We're about to be so rich, you're gonna be like, "College? What?"
我叫鲍比
My name is Bobbi.
鲍比
Hey, Bobbi.
这样做是为了大家好  相信我  好吗
I'm doing this for us. Just, uh... Just trust me, okay?
天哪  你还好吗
Christ, are you ok?
你做梦了吗
Were you dreaming?
没有
No.
我到家了
This is home.
好漂亮啊
Oh, it's so pretty.
尼娅
Nia!
亲爱的
Oh, honey.
-你看起来好饿  -她多美啊
- You look famished. - She looks lovely.
一如既往
As always.
而且很潮
And chic.
-这位城里妞是谁  -姐姐
- Who is this city girl? - Hi!
她到底对我妹做了什么
What has she done with my sister?
梅芙  妈  爸
Uh, Maeve, Mom, Dad,
这是我的朋友兼老板  卡拉·丹弗斯
I want you to meet my friend and boss, Kara Danvers.
幸会
Nice to meet you.
卡拉  你能来太好了
Kara, we're so delighted you came.
-你们家真漂亮  -谢谢
- Your home is beautiful. - Thank you.
-卡拉  你喜欢小萝卜吗  -喜欢
- Kara, do you like radishes? - Uh... Yeah.
伊莎贝尔做的小萝卜很出名的
Isabel's radishes are legendary.
好吧
Okay. Okay.
有其母必有其女
And the apple doesn't fall far from the tree.
梅芙尽得她妈妈的真传
Maeve's got all her mom's gifts.
看看她的兰花
Look at her orchids.
妈妈天生聪慧
Mom's a natural.
我要很努力才能记住三万种兰花
I've labored to memorize the 30,000 species of orchids.
亲爱的  你还穿开裆裤时就是个小神通了
Sweetheart, you have been a prodigy since you were in diapers.
应该说  从穿开裆裤起  我就是你的门徒了吧
More like your protege since I was in diapers.
尼娅
Nia.
老妈在教我画日本水墨画  那是我的墨水
Mom's teaching me Japanese ink wash painting. That was my ink.
对不起  我不知道我为什么要拿起来
Uh... I'm sorry. I... I don't know why I did that.
你可能是累了
I think you're tired.
我们开了很久的车  她肯定饿坏了
We had a long drive, and she's definitely famished.
保罗  那是西班牙大锅饭吗
Paul, is that paella?
我想不到尼娅会在凯特科杂志上班
You know, I can't believe our Nia works at CatCo.
凯特的书你看了多少遍
You've read Cat's book how many times?
-十四遍吧  -真的吗
- Fourteen? - Really?
是四十遍吧
More like 40.
当记者一直是尼娅的梦想
It was always Nia's dream to be a journalist.
从事情的实质出发  去做出改变
To be in the center of things, to effect change.
我们有些人反而喜欢远离喧嚣
Some of us actually like it far from the madding crowd.
-那你住在帕瑟斯吗  -我就住在这条街上
- So, you live here in Parthas? - I live just down the street.
我是妈妈的学徒  我开了一间画室
I apprentice with Mom, and I own a painting studio.
我一直在看这些画
I've been staring at these paintings all day.
-这些都是你画的吗  -是老妈画的
- Are they yours? - They are Mom's.
她画的是她的梦境
She paints her dreams.
只要我的梦境灵感降临  我也会画的
So will I, once my dreams finally kick in.
这种事急不来  亲爱的
You can't rush things, honey.
尼娅有和你说过我们家奇怪的遗传吗  卡拉
Has Nia told you about our strange family legacy, Kara?
梦见未来的超能力
The otherworldly dreaming powers?
她有提过
She's mentioned it.
梦见未来是由母系遗传
Dreaming the future is passed down on the matrilineal line.
每一代中都有一位女性会遗传到这个天赋
One woman from every generation inherits the gift.
-只有一个吗  -对  只有一个
- Just one? - Yeah. Just one.
当然  除非她遭到诅咒  无法预见未来
Unless, of course, she's cursed with future blindness.
在这种情况下  这一代就不会得到遗传
In which case it skips a generation.
不会这样的  梅芙
That's not going to happen, Maeve.
我和你说了  在我怀着你的时候
I told you, when I was pregnant with you,
我梦到我的女儿会拥有这个天赋
I dreamt that my daughter would have the gift.
只是时间问题
Just give it time.
又接到两起暴力袭击事件的报告
There are reports of two more rage attacks.
事态愈演愈烈
It's spreading.
我们要立刻加派小队出去支援
We need to get more teams out there immediately.
收到  而且这些爆发似乎是有预谋的
Copy. Also, it appears these outbursts were intentional.
人们有意购买这种毒品吗
People are buying this drug on purpose?
怎么会  为什么
How? And why?
我应该早就想到的
I should have been ahead of this.
布莱尼  我不在状态
Brainy, I'm off.
我有点不对劲
Something is wrong with me.
我脑子里好像缺少了一些什么
I mean, it's like, something in my mind, it's missing.
荣恩  谢谢你来
J'onn, thank you for coming.
当然  你在电话里惊慌失措
Sure. You sounded panicked on the phone.
你没事吧
Is everything all right?
我的思路不清晰
I'm not thinking clearly,
我不能犯错
and I can't afford to be making mistakes.
-我能怎么帮你呢  -扫描我
- Well, how can I help? - Scan me.
扫描我的大脑
My mind.
为什么
Why?
我有些不对劲  荣恩
Something is wrong with me, J'onn.
我... 我不知道怎么形容
Can I-I-I... I don't know how to describe it,
就是觉得脱节了
I just feel disconnected.
我觉得很脆弱
I feel vulnerable.
如果我遇到求真者的时候
I mean, look, what if something went wrong
出了什么问题呢
when I underwent the Truth Seeker?
我知道不应该有后遗症什么的
I know there's not supposed to be side effects or anything,
但问题就是从那时开始的
but that's when this began.
我只是要知道我没事
I just need to know that I'm okay.
如果我有事  我也要知道我没疯
And if I'm not okay, I just need to know that I'm not crazy.
帮帮我吧  荣恩
Please, J'onn.
-这是梅芙以前的房间  -好漂亮
- This is Maeve's old room. - It's so pretty.
《荣格论梦》  《梦想词典》
Jung and Dreams, Lexicon of Dreams...
我明白你为什么不告诉梅芙
Well, I understand why you haven't told Maeve
你遗传了梦境超能力
that you inherited the powers.
对吧  她肯定会难过死的
Right? It's a disaster.
我根本不想要这个超能力
I never even wanted the powers.
我一直想去外面的世界
I always wanted to be out in the world,
报道新闻  帮助人们
reporting, helping people.
你的超能力可以给人提供很大的帮助
Well, you can help people in a big way with your powers.
梅芙一生都在学习破译梦境
Maeve's been studying the language of dreams her whole life.
这个超能力是她梦寐以求的
This is all she's ever wanted.
这样会伤透她的心
This will break her heart.
如果每一代只有一个女儿
If the powers are only passed
能遗传到这个超能力
to one daughter per generation,
他们为什么这么肯定是遗传给梅芙了
why are they so sure that it's Maeve?
你也听到我妈说了
You heard my mom.
在她怀着梅芙的时候
When she was pregnant with Maeve,
她梦到她的女儿会成为梦想者
she dreamt that her daughter would be the Dreamer.
相信我  我知道要伤害你姐姐很难
Believe me, I know how hard it is to hurt your sister,
但是我认为你应该告诉她
but I think you should tell her.
我会和我妈聊聊
I'm going to talk to my mom.
我要看看有没有办法
I'm gonna see if there's a way
把超能力转移给梅芙
that I can transfer the powers to Maeve somehow.
我觉得这是不可能的
I don't think it works like that.
你能去和我姐姐聊一会吗
Could you just talk to my sister?
采访一下她
Interview her for your article?
帮我争取点时间  让我和我妈聊聊
Just buy me some time with my mom?
当然可以
Okay. Of course.
记忆消除应该是无迹可寻的
The mind wipe should be untraceable.
但可能是因为艾丽克斯和超女的关系
But it's possible because Alex's relationship with Supergirl
跟其他人的不一样
is unlike anyone else's,
她与求真者的相遇
her encounter with the Truth Seeker
可能在她身上留下了无法鉴别的强烈念想
may have left her with an unidentifiable itch.
你不能告诉她超女的身份已经删除了
You can't tell her that Supergirl's identity has been removed.
哈雷还在调查超女的真实身份
Haley is still on a mission to find out who Supergirl is.
我知道  我知道
I know. I know.
但是有时安慰剂也许会很有效
But, uh, sometimes a placebo can be very effective.
你要骗她
You're going to lie to her.
我也不想
I don't want to.
但这样也许能给她的内心带去平静
But maybe it'll bring her peace of mind,
帮助她恢复
help her heal.
-你准备好了吗  -嗯
- Are you ready? - Yeah.
谢谢你帮我  荣恩
Thanks for doing this, J'onn.
-开始了  -好
- All right. - Okay.
你没事  一切都正常
You're fine. Everything is normal.
真的吗  感谢上帝
Really? Thank God.
好
Okay.
也许你在工作上感到有压力
Perhaps the stress you're feeling at work is,
是因为缺少一个搭档
uh, the lack of a partner.
配合你唱白脸的红脸搭档
A good cop to your bad cop.
或许我需要的不是警察
Or maybe I need the opposite of a cop.
布莱尼  你的演技如何
Brainy, how are your acting skills?
从没想过凯特科会引用我的话
I never thought I'd be quoted in CatCo.
那你跟我说说在帕瑟斯的生活吧
So, tell me what it's like to live in Parthas?
大多数帕瑟斯人从来没离开过那里
Most people from Parthas never leave.
尼娅是为数不多离开的人
Nia's one of the few.
她无所畏惧
She's fearless.
我一直很羡慕她
I've always been envious of that.
我们都有各自的天赋
We all have our own gifts.
我妈妈用她的天赋养育这里
My mom chose to use her gifts to nurture this town.
而我的外婆
But my grandmother, on Naltor,
是纳尔托尔星上的英雄
she was the hero of the planet.
就像超女一样
Like Supergirl.
等我的能力派上用场  我就想当那种英雄
When my powers kick in, I want to be that kind of hero.
我想可能当英雄也没那么爽吧
Well, I think maybe being a hero isn't all it's cracked up to be.
自由之子  在这里
Children of Liberty? Here?
每年收获节
Every year at Harvest Fest,
隔壁镇上的混球就过来抗议
jerks from neighboring towns come and protest.
他们讨厌人类和外星人在一块
They hate humans and aliens mixing.
不管你有什么好东西
When you have something good,
总有人会想毁了它
there's always going to be people who want to tear it down.
别担心  帕瑟斯人能保护好自己
Don't worry, the citizens of Parthas can take care of themselves.
-哥们  -你是谁
- Bros? - Who are you?
我们昨晚在你的小屋见过
We met last night at your humble abode.
-嗑药暴怒者  顺便说一句  -你怎么在这里
- Sick rager, BT-dubs. - Why are you in here?
跟你一样  我拿到了甜甜暴怒糖
Like you, I scored some of that sweet, sweet rage candy.
接下来我就只记得
The next thing I know,
跟先生你一块被丢到这来了
I'm tossed in here with you fine gentlemen.
不管你干什么  别跟那女巫说一个字
Well, whatever you do, don't breathe a word to that witch.
当然  我绝对不会
Of course not. I would never.
或许我们出去之后
Perhaps, once we're out,
可以再找些暴怒药片  然后  暴怒一番
we could find some more of those rage pills and, well, rage.
不  我不干那个了
No, I'm done with that stuff.
如果杰瑞和凯文聪明点
Besides, if Jerry and Kev are smart,
他们就会跳到那货车里  逃出镇去
they jumped in that van and got the hell out of town.
杰瑞和凯文
Jerry and Kev.
真简单
That was easy.
厉害  花了两分钟就搞到信息了
Impressive. It took you less than two minutes to get that information.
你怎么学会说"哥们"这种话的
How did you learn to speak Dude-bro?
就跟他们一样  电影里学的
The same way they did. The movies.
这一切  多谢你们了
Well, thank you. Both of you. For everything.
嗯
Yeah.
趁他们没再搞破坏  我们去抓住他们
Now let's catch these guys before they can do any more damage.
我真想你
I miss you so much.
我根本无法理解
I can never understand how
你怎么会喜欢住那种混凝土丛林
you enjoy living in that concrete jungle.
城市也有生命力
There's a life force to the city.
虽然不像大自然  但它也有活力
It's not the same as nature, but it's alive.
你好像很习惯城市节奏嘛
You seem in tune with the energy of the city.
很适合你
It suits you.
谢谢
Thanks.
妈妈  说到活力
Mom, speaking of energy, um...
我跟卡拉聊了梦境的能力
I was talking to Kara about the dream powers...
她很好奇
And she was wondering, just out of curiosity,
在我这年纪  如果你不想要这种能力
if you didn't want the powers when you were my age,
有办法拒绝吗
was there a way that you could've refused them?
没有
No.
那要是你真的不想使用能力呢
But what if you really didn't want to use them?
你想把它给别人呢
What if you needed to direct them to somebody else?
梦想者是天生的
The Dreamer is destined.
被选中的人不能做出选择
The chosen one doesn't have a choice.
这是她与生俱来的
It's in her blood.
妈妈  妈妈
Mom? Mom?
天哪  它咬了你  妈妈  妈妈
Oh, no, it bit you. Mom? Mom?
妈妈
Mom?
尼娅  是你
Nia, it's you.
我的天哪
Oh, my God.
妈妈  怎么回事
Mom, what's happening?
你在我的梦里
You're in my dream.
我快死了  宝贝
I'm dying, my love.
你是下一个梦想者
You are the next Dreamer.
不  不
No, no.
当然是你了  必须是你
Of course it's you. It had to be you.
对不起  我一直没有意识到
I'm sorry I was so blind.
我的梦中  我的女儿有能力...
My dream of my daughter with powers...
我从没见过她的脸
I never saw her face.
妈妈  我不在乎
Mom, I don't care about that.
-我还没准备好离开你  -你准备好了
- I'm not ready for you to go. - You are ready.
我的元素是水  你的是火
My element was water. Yours is fire.
你的火会令你比我强大的多
And your fire will make you far more powerful than I ever was.
你命中注定要成为我的女儿
It was your destiny to be my daughter.
成为梦想者
To be Dreamer.
你人生中经历的考验都是为了成就你
Life put you through many trials just to be who you are.
它让你强大
It made you strong.
你的力量会助你成为英雄
That strength will serve you well as a hero.
我的尼娅
My Nia.
尼娅
Nia.
尼娅  醒醒
Nia. Wake up.
她没有呼吸了
She's not breathing.
妈妈...
Mom...
对不起
I'm so sorry.
尼娅
Nia.
你必须醒来
You've got to get out.
妈妈去世的消息传开了
Words spread about mom
镇子把收获节改成了临时的追悼会
and the town's turning Harvest Fest into an impromptu memorial.
-我拉不上裙子  -我来帮你
- I can't zip this dress. - Let me help you.
都是我的错
It's my fault.
我现在应该拥有能力了  尼娅
I should have gotten the powers by now, Nia.
事情不对劲
It doesn't make sense.
我是说  可能...
I mean, maybe...
可能是我做错什么了
Maybe I'm doing something wrong.
你什么都没有做错
Of course you're not doing anything wrong.
一定是的
I must be.
如果我有能力  我就会梦见妈妈有危险
If I had the powers, I would have dreamed Mom was in danger.
我本可以阻止的
I could have prevented it.
就算你梦见了
Even if you had a dream,
你也不一定能理解梦的意思...
you don't know if you could have interpreted it--
我当然能
Of course I could have.
我精通梦的解析
I'm fluent in dream interpretation.
我本可以警告妈妈有危险  我本可以...
I would have been forewarned about Mom, I would have...
我本可以救她的
I would have saved her.
你快穿衣服吧
You've got to get dressed.
詹姆斯  我在这呢
Yeah, James. I'm over here.
莉娜  我有事想跟你谈谈
Hey, Lena, I want to talk to you about something.
什么事
What's that?
游戏之夜的训练
Game night training.
什么  行吧  听着
What? Okay, listen, some
有的情侣需要培养交流技巧
couples need to work on their communication skills
还有的情侣需要培养问答游戏的竞争技巧
and others need to work on their competitive trivia skills.
而你跟我亲密无间  奥尔森先生
You and I are deeply connected, Mr. Olsen.
我们只需要游戏之夜上表现一番
We just need our game night performance to reflect that.
-而你讨厌输  -我讨厌输
- And you hate to lose. - And I hate to lose.
所以  你来不来
So, are you in?
-来  -很好  那么首先
- I'm all in. - Excellent. All right, first up,
经典摇滚版"打破砂锅问到底"
Trivial Pursuit Classic Rock edition.
等一下  你之前想跟我说什么来着
Wait, hold on. Um, what was it you wanted to talk to me about?
晚点再说
It can wait.
五  六  七  八...
Five, six, seven, eight...
我们错过了机会  我以为你说我们完了
We just missed our turn. I thought you said we were done.
计划有变  小吱
Change of plans, Little Squeak.
我们收到了一份无法拒绝的报价
We got an offer we couldn't resist.
一万元  现金
Ten thousand in cold, hard cash.
保持警惕  我们马上回来  好吗
Hang tight. We'll be right back, okay?
你好  先生
Hello, good sir.
我叫凯文  这是我同伙
My name is Kevin, this is my associate.
你带了货吗
You have the stuff?
你带了现金吗
Do you have the cash?
来吧  伙计们  我们得到了我们要的
Come on, boys. We got what we need.
我们去那个庆典仪式收获蟑螂吧
Let's get to that festival and harvest these roaches.
-你好  布莱尼  -你好  荣恩
- Hey, Brainy. - Greetings, J'onn.
我来看看艾丽克斯的情况  你见到她了吗
I came to see how Alex was feeling. Have you seen her?
还没有
I have not.
但我找到了药贩子的货车
But I have located our dealers' van.
布莱尼  太好了
Brainy, that's great.
我也找到了丹弗斯局长
I have also located Director Danvers.
满是胜利的一天啊
A day of many victories.
一开始我没发现嫌疑人登记的车辆
Now, at first I found no vehicle registered to our suspects,
我觉得斯彭斯可能在撒谎
and I thought perhaps Spence was lying.
他就像做这事的人
Which would be so like him.
但后来我发现了这个...
But then I found this...
最初登记的是一位女士
Originally registered to a Mrs.
维罗妮卡·"罗尼"·米勒  已经去世了
Veronica "Roni" Miller, now deceased.
名头后来传给了罗伯塔·米勒
The title has then passed to Roberta Miller,
杰瑞·米勒的妹妹
Jerry Miller's little sister.
干得好  好了  我们走  各位
Good work. All right, let's move, people.
你想趁猫不在的时候占便宜吗
Hey, you wanna take advantage while the cat's away and roll with?
有了这样的愤怒  我们可以利用一个和平的人
With all this rage going on, we could use a man of peace.
-当然  你看起来好多了  -是的  多谢了你
- Sure. You seem better. - I am. Thanks to you.
我应该穿梅芙的裙子吗
I'm supposed to wear one of Maeve's dresses?
我还要从她那里拿走什么
What else am I going to take from her?
你不能为此自责
You can't blame yourself for this.
我撒谎了
I lied.
我在开车时做了个梦
I did have a dream on the car ride.
我梦到我妈妈喝了墨黑色液体然后化成了灰
I dreamt my mom drank an inky black fluid and turned into ash.
所以我毁了梅芙的美术用品
That's why I trashed Maeve's art supplies.
但我确实用了毒墨水
But I took the poison ink literally.
只是死亡的象征而已
It was only a symbol of death.
如果我像姐姐一样费心学习
I would have known that
我本该知道的
if I had bothered to study, like my sister.
到处都是这些其他的符号
There were all of these other symbols,
我无法解码  就像蜘蛛网一样
things I couldn't decode, cobwebs.
成吨的蜘蛛网  蜘蛛们结网
Tons of cobwebs. Spiders spin webs.
我本该知道墨水只是一种象征
I should've known that the ink was only a symbol,
蜘蛛才是真正的危险
that the spiders were the real danger.
梅芙本该知道
Maeve would've known that.
梅芙本该得到超能力
Maeve should have gotten the powers.
尼娅  别对自己这么做
Nia, don't do this to yourself.
我不能告诉她我有超能力
I can't ever tell her I have them.
请听我说  对你姐姐保密
Hey. Please, listen to me. Keeping a secret from your sister
只会对你造成最深的伤害
will only hurt you more than anything else.
你没有拿走她的任何东西
You didn't take anything from her.
你不是自己选择成为有超能力的妹妹
You didn't choose to be the sister with powers.
她迟早会理解的
In time, she'll understand that.
但现在  你要对她诚实
But, right now, you have to be honest with her.
你是对的
You're right.
我会告诉她
I'll tell her.
在追悼会之后
After the memorial.
我肯定这就是
I was certain this was the
罗伯塔·米勒的货车的最近位置
last confirmed location of Roberta Miller's van.
我觉得是的  看起来像已经有人替你做了事
I think it was. Looks like somebody already did your job for you.
杰瑞·米勒  凯文·哈金斯
Jerry Miller? Kevin Huggins?
你们因贩卖不明外星物质而被捕
You're under arrest for selling an unidentified alien substance.
搜他们的身
Search them.
不  你什么都找不到  我们被抢了
No, you won't find anything. We were robbed.
-被谁  -我不知道
- By who? - I don't know.
他们说要攻击某个外星人庆典
They said something about attacking some alien festival?
我就怕这个
This is what I was afraid of.
布莱尼  抓住他们
Brainy, take 'em in.
不不不  等等  拜托  我妹妹...
No, no, no. Wait, wait. Please. My little sister...
她开着货车跟在他们后面
She took the van and went after them.
-她为什么要这么做  -我不知道  为了保护我
- Why would she do that? - I don't know, to defend me?
为了复仇
To get revenge?
她疯了
She was mad.
她开走了  甚至没有为我们停车
She bailed out and didn't even stop for us.
谁知道小吱有那么愤怒
Who knew that Squeak had that much rage?
我知道
I did.
鲍比很敏感
Bobbi's sensitive.
人们对这一点下手  你知道吗
People prey on that, you know?
她在学校被人排挤
She got pushed around at school,
在家里也被人排挤
got pushed around at home, too.
是个人都会愤怒
It'd make anyone angry.
帕瑟斯  和平之城
梅芙  你和卡拉先走吧
Maeve, why don't you and Kara go on ahead?
我们会赶上的
We'll catch up.
这是什么
What's this?
可能听着奇怪
This is going to sound strange,
但是我昨晚做了个梦
but, um, I had a dream last night.
你妈妈来找我  说这是给你的
Your mom came to me, said this was for you.
在帕瑟斯  有人去世的时候
In Parthas, when someone passes,
我们会穿白色的衣服纪念每个人的光芒
we wear white to honor the light in each of us.
人类和外星人一样
Humans and aliens alike.
见过我妈妈的人都知道  她的光芒很耀眼
Anyone who met my mom knows her light was blinding.
我很幸运每天都能沐浴其中
I'm so lucky I got to bask in it every single day.
我也很幸运能够跟随她的脚步
And I'm so lucky to follow in her footsteps,
继续她的事业  继承她的遗产...
continue her work, carry on her legacy...
梅芙  当心
Maeve, watch out!
梅芙
Maeve!
你知道那把斧头会砍上讲台
You knew that ax was going to hit the podium.
你有这种超能力
You have the powers.
-我可以解释  -别碰我
- I can explain. - Don't touch me.
救命  救命
Help! Help!
被堵住了  走这边
It's blocked. Come this way.
这边
This way.
头低下  快走
Keep your heads down. Come on.
扣留所有的入侵者
Detain all aggressors.
荣恩  把人们从屋子里带出来
J'onn, get the people out of that barn.
鲍比·米勒
Bobbi Miller?
放她走  放她走
Hey! Let her go. I said, let her go!
这是给你的最后警告
This is your final warning.
不  丹弗斯局长  不
No! Director Danvers, don't!
超女  你袭击了一个美国军方特工
Supergirl, you struck an agent of the United States military.
可你准备射杀一个无辜的外星人
And you were about to shoot down an innocent alien.
我控制着一个不稳定的外星人  你插手了
I was containing a volatile alien, and you interfered.
那个外星人只是在保卫他的家
That alien was just defending his home.
这些山寨自由之子在激怒他
These... These Children of Liberty wannabes were provoking him.
他们袭击了一个和平的追悼会
They attacked a peaceful memorial.
我们不听你的话了
Your word no longer works for us.
而我有任务在身
And I have a job to do.
就是去揭露所有事实
That's to uncover all of the facts.
而那个女孩  她不是自由之子
And that girl, she is not a Child of Liberty,
她只是个靠毒品来发泄怒气的孩子
she's just a kid who took a drug to fuel her rage.
-为什么有人  -因为这个世界
- Why would someone-- - Because this world is filled
有许多人都比她强大
with a lot of people that are bigger and stronger than her.
而那种脆弱感会让你愤怒
And that kind of vulnerability, it makes you angry.
当你无能为力时
And when you feel powerless enough,
你为了感受力量而不择手段
you will do anything it takes to feel strong.
我能理解
I can understand that.
是吗  怎么会
Really? How?
你几乎被形容成钢铁女侠
You are literally described as the Girl of Steel.
不管是外在还是内心
On the outside and the in.
你真的认为我不知道
You really think I don't
脆弱是什么感觉吗
know what it feels like to be vulnerable?
是的
No, I don't.
现在  你要么站到一边去  不然我连你也抓
Now, you either stand down, or I will arrest you, too.
来吧
Come on.
我快准备好了  就想跟我姐姐谈谈
I'm almost ready to go. I just need to talk to my sister.
-当然  我来拿  -谢谢
- Of course. Here. - Thanks.
没什么好谈的
There's nothing to talk about.
梅芙  我发誓我是要告诉你的
Maeve, I swear I was going to tell you.
是吗  什么时候
Really? When?
在追悼会之后
After the memorial service.
几个月前你就知道了
You knew for months.
这几个月来  我一直因为没有能力
For months you let me go on about
而难过不已  而你却放任自流
how upset I was that the powers hadn't kicked in yet.
你让我受到羞辱  以为自己看不到未来
You let me humiliate myself, think I was future blind--
不不  不是这样的
No, no. It wasn't like that.
我是在想办法给能力传给你
I was trying to transfer the powers to you somehow.
是这样哦
Right.
你怎么  怎么是你  你怎么会有能力
How did you, of all people, get the powers?
这种能力应该是由母亲传给女儿
They're supposed to be passed down from mother to daughter.
像你这样的人是怎么得到它们的
So how did someone like you get them?
你甚至都不是个真正的女人
You're not even a real woman.
梅芙一直是我最强大的支持者
Maeve was always my biggest supporter.
我不相信她会说出那种话
I can't believe she'd say something like that.
尼娅  我很遗憾
Nia, I'm so sorry.
我知道她会因为没有能力而难过
I knew she was gonna be crushed about the powers, but...
卡拉  她是那么的愤怒
Kara, she was so angry.
我知道这不是一码事
I know it's not the same thing,
但要是能让你好受点的话
but if it makes you feel any better,
我和我姐姐也经历了很多事
I've been through a lot with my sister.
我感谢你的支持
I appreciate your support,
但是这不是你能了解的
but this isn't something that you can understand.
我有外星人能力  而我姐姐没有
I have alien powers, my sister doesn't.
而现在  她恨我
And now, she hates me.
你为什么停车
Why are you pulling over?
卡拉  你在做什么
Kara, what are you doing?
我能理解
I do understand.
大概比任何人都能理解
Probably better than anyone.
我就是超女
I am Supergirl.
几乎没人知道我的真实身份
Very few people know my true identity
因为对他们来说不安全
because it's not safe for them to.
但我告诉你是因为我觉得这能帮助你
But I'm telling you because I think it can help you.
我也觉得这不会伤害你
And I don't think it will harm you.
你  也是位英雄
You, too, are a hero.
我是有能力的妹妹
I was the sister with powers.
我亲眼看见艾丽克斯在很多方面付出了代价
And I watched Alex pay the price for it in so many ways.
大多数时候  她都处理好了
Most of the time, she handled it with grace,
但我告诉你  有时候局面会很难看
but I'll tell you, there were some times that it got ugly.
在我们还是孩子是
When we were younger...
甚至是现在都有过
And even now.
但我相信两姐妹之间的爱
But I have faith that the love between two sisters
最终会战胜一切
will prevail in the end.
我必须相信这点
I have to believe that.
我要让你知道你并不孤单
I just need you to know now that you are not alone.
你是有家人的
You have a family.
你有我
You have me.
你想见我吗  老板
You wanted to see me, boss?
坐
Have a seat.
麦肯齐  我  我
Look, Mackenzie, I... I, um,
看过你发给我的L公司资料了
went over the materials you sent me for L-Corp
所有都是正常的
and everything checks out.
食药管局的一切都是光明正大的
Everything is aboveboard with the FDA.
我的消息来源是错了
I guess my source was wrong.
奇怪  他很靠谱的
Weird, he's usually solid.
别对自己太苛刻
Don't be so hard on yourself.
这是常有的事  这是个学习的过程
Look, these things happen. It's a learning process.
但你先来找我是正确的
But you were right to come to me first.
你的直觉很好
You have great instincts.
清除记忆改变了艾丽克斯
The mind wipe did change Alex.
我以为再骗她一次会有帮助
I thought lying to her one more time would help,
但情况更遭了
but it goes deeper than that.
她认知的变化是种症状
The disconnection was a symptom.
艾丽克斯从小和外星人妹妹一起长大
Alex grew up with a sister from another planet.
一个超级英雄
A superhero.
没有了那段记忆
Without that memory,
没有了与他人的接触  她的观念改变了
that exposure to other, her perception has changed.
-她的共感变了  -为什么  我不懂
- Her empathy has shifted. - Why? I don't get it.
她和很多外星人都很亲近
She's close with plenty of other aliens.
你是艾丽克斯成长过程中所拥有的基础关系
You were Alex's primary relationship during her formative years.
那就塑造了她对外星人的看法
It's what formed her view of aliens.
而我们正好把那些抹除了
And that's what we've erased.
那些融于血脉的记忆
That blood memory.
我只能相信  在内心深处她还是我们的艾丽克斯
I have to believe that deep down, she's still our Alex.
我们别无选择  现在只能坚强起来了
We did what we had to do, and now we have to be strong.
为了她
For her.
这正是我需要的
Now this is exactly what I need.
这周末的事之后  我只想
After the weekend I've had, all I want to do is
花点时间和我最爱的两人
spend some time and relax with my two favorite people
一起看史上最棒的电影放松放松
and the greatest movie of all time.
我不确定看《终结者》能不能放松  但也行
I'm not sure The Terminator is relaxing, but okay.
是《终结者2》  还有很有罪恶感的美食
Uh, T2. And it's comfort food.
-你的手  -对了
- Your hand. - Oh. Yes.
超女送的离别礼物
Well, that is a lovely parting gift from Supergirl.
我希望你的周末会好点
I hope your weekend was better.
荣恩说你有个任务  怎么样
Oh, J'onn said you were on assignment. How did that go?
我跟进的那个事没成功
Oh! The story I was following didn't really pan out.
今晚我们不谈论工作  好不好
Hey, how about we don't actually talk about work tonight?
-对  -可以的
- Yeah. - I could do that.
现在  不想死的话  就看电影吧
Now, watch the movie if you don't want to die.
应该是"你想活下来的话"
It's "If you want to live."
-错了  -你个笨蛋
- Oh, shoot. - Oh, you goober.
卡兹尼亚
我们有麻烦了
我要联系一个人
那人在美国